C. Carlo Fazioli

Washington D.C. © 626.298.1212 🗓 carlofazioli.com

I am an applied mathematician and software engineering generalist with experience in cloud computing, AI, and DevOps. I am a lifelong learner with far-ranging interests, confident in my ability to rapidly spin up in new environments, as well as deep-dive into the gritty details. In 2021, I made it onto the Advent Of Code global leaderboard!

Current Position

2018 – Present **Software Engineer**, *Group W, Inc.*, Vienna VA.

Presently, Product Owner migrating a Kubernetes application from a privately controlled compute cluster to Microsoft Azure.

- Initially created and currently maintaining the DevOps pipeline:
 - Git branching strategy
 - Issue management
 - Azure infrastructure deployment
 - Source code and Docker image builds
- Testing and QA
- Application installation
- Technical documentation
- Architected and currently maintaining the application's cloud infrastructure:
 - Virtual Networking
 - **DNS Zones**
 - Kubernetes Cluster

- Docker Container Registry
- Azure Active Directory
- Security Principals

- Utilizing modern toolchain:
 - Git and GitLab CICD
 - Azure ARM Templates

- Kubernetes and Helm
- Let's Encrypt SSL Certificates

Previously, developer on a 2021 MORS Barchi-prize-winning, multi-year, multi-million dollar DARPA contract to develop an AI wargaming application deployed to a 11-node, 1,240-CPU cluster.

- Architected microservices, their interfaces, and their implementations as Kubernetes objects.
- Designed AI algorithms under senior mathematician's guidance, using reinforcement learning, feature engineering, TensorFlow neural networks, and Monte Carlo Tree Search.
- Wrote application source code in python, including REST API with Django, database interfaces with PyMongo, and custom libraries.
- o Acted as Agile Team Leader, managing GitLab issues, branching strategy, merging strategies and timelines, package releases, and CICD pipelines for a team of 10.
- o Administrated multiple MongoDB instances (each 10GB-1TB) from the mongo shell, and with PyMongo.

Education

2005 – 2009 Ph.D. Mathematics, University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago IL.

2000 – 2004 B.S. Mathematics, University of San Francisco, San Francisco CA.

Previous Positions

2016 – 2018 **Econometric Modeler**, *International Monetary Fund*, Washington DC.

Collaborated with IMF economists on economic model development; researched, designed, and implemented algorithms for use by IMF staff; pursued exploratory research into technology solutions for IMF institutional needs; addressed technical needs of individual IMF staff.

2013 - 2016 Assistant Teaching Professor, Dept. of Mathematics, Drexel University, Philadelphia, PA. Developed course and lab materials; lectured, graded exams, monitored students' use of online resources, assigned final grades; assisted students as needed outside of class or in office hours; directed teaching assistants.

2011 – 2013 **Postdoctoral Research Associate**, *Dept. of Mathematical Sciences*, New Jersey Inst. of Tech., Newark, NJ.

Researched, designed, and coded novel algorithms for use in fluid dynamics simulations; briefed research supervisor; presented findings to collaborators and conference attendees.

Hobbies and Interests

- Solving the NYT crossword puzzle daily
- o Running, cycling, and yoga
- Cloud computing
- Science fiction lit/TV/movies
- Advent of Code and CTFs
- Bug bountying and cybersecurity
- MCU and embedded systems
- Quantum computing